Dung (Shayne) Nguyen

Master Graduand in Economics · The University of Hong Kong

📞 (+852) 6890-3932 🔛 dungtn@connect.hku.hk 😯 dungnd.site 🛮 in Dung Nguyen

Summary.

Dung (Shayne) Nguyen, is a postgraduate student in Economics at The University of Hong Kong (HKU). Before attending HKU, he graduated as a member of the inaugural cohort of Fulbright University Vietnam. Dung is interested in applying econometrics, machine learning, and textual analysis to analyze socioeconomic events. During his university years, he worked in non-profit organizations, research institutions, the educational sector, and consulting firms.

Research Interest_

Primary fields, Quantitative Methods, Development Economics Secondary fields, Political Economy

Education

The University of Hong Kong

Pokfulam, Hong Kong

MASTER OF ECONOMICS

2023 - Expected 2024

- Grade: 3.68/4.3
- Relevant Coursework: Advanced Microeconomics (C), Introduction to Econometrics (B+), Advanced Macroeconomics (A), Statistical Learning (A+), Causal Inference (A+), Advanced Econometrics (B+), Textual Analysis For Economist (A+), Applied Machine Learning (B+), and Modern Econometrics For Business (A-), and Development Economics (A+).

Fulbright University Vietnam

HCMC, Vietnam

BACHELOR OF ARTS, HONOURS APPLIED ECONOMICS

2019 - 2023

- Grade: 3.77/4.0 (Highest Grade for Senior Thesis)
- Thesis: Determinants of individuals' participation and contribution to the voluntary social insurance fund: Evidence from Vietnam.
- Quantitative Coursework: Statistics (A), Linear Algebra (A-), Calculus (B+), Probability Theory (A), Econometrics (A), Machine Learning (A), and Deep Learning (A).

Research Experience

Vietnam Chamber of Commerce and Industry (VCCI)

Hybrid

ECONOMICS CONSULTANT

July 2024 - Now

- · Support Dr.Tuan-Ngoc Phan and VCCI team to research on the impacts of regional linkages in improving the business environment, environmental protection, sustainable development, FDI and investment.
- · Collaborate with the team to create a macroeconomics report for local governments of four provinces including Quang Ninh, Hai Phong, Hai Duong, and Hung Yen.

Fulbright University Vietnam

HCMC, Vietnam

RESEARCH COLLABORATOR

Sept 2023 - Now

- Project: Vietnam GSO Enterprise Survey.
- Support Dr.Tuan-Ngoc Phan and Prof.Markus Taussig to interpret and document the largest firm-level data of Vietnam.
- · Manipulate and compile firm-level panel data during 2003-2018 with more than 1M samples to extract insights for relevant research projects in business and political economy.

YSEALI Academy at Fulbright University Vietnam

HCMC, Vietnam

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE INTERN

RESEARCH INTERN

Oct 2022 - Aug 2023

- · Project: Digital Proxy War.
- · Supported Dr.Willem Smit to research the internationalization strategies of Digital Giants from the US and China.
- Performed quantitative analysis on a time-series dataset of 91 app downloads from more than 30 different markets.
- · Conducted market research, analyzing academic, business case study, and other ad-hoc tasks to deduce insights for the research.

Vietnam Institute of Economics

Hanoi, Vietnam

• Project: Vietnam Social Pension Fund Sustainability: Current problems and future implications.

- May 2021 Oct 2021
- · Developed model with different demographic scenarios to forecast and evaluate the financial sustainability of the Social Pension Reserve Fund of Vietnam until 2047.
- · Utilized ILO materials focused on actuarial valuation methods for national security schemes and literature review to address possible policy changes to improve the Social Insurance Reserve Fund performance.

SHAYNE NGUYEN · CV JULY 18, 2024

Professional Experience

Sun Life Hong Kong

Internal Audit Intern March 2024 – June 2024

- · Supported the internal audit team to work on data analytics tests for current audit projects in Hong Kong.
- Established a data analytics library for Hong Kong projects and formalize new procedures for audit projects involving analytics testing.
- Developed an Excel database for all audit projects of Sun Life (on a global scale) to build a dashboard that provides descriptive statistics and relevant patterns derived from the data.

Dalberg AdvisorsVietnam & Hong Kong

ANALYST (FULL-TIME)

July 2023 - Sept 2023

- · Supported leadership team to establish working policy and grow Dalberg's first office in Vietnam.
- · Led 2 desk research projects with a focus on AI Impact areas, including AI & education and AI & foundation across Asia-Pacific.
- · Advised Google For Education team and relevant stakeholders to implement AI education projects in East Asia.

Panl Vietnam & Singapore

PROJECT TEAM ASSISTANT

May 2022 – Jan 2023

- Worked under the supervision of former BCG partner and associate to advise on deal structure and facilitate strategic partnership between two of Vietnam's top 20 largest companies on a loyalty joint venture worth over US\$1B.
- Conducted market research, business case study & quantitative analysis to deduce key findings and make high-level recommendations on building digital loyalty program.

CoderSchool HCMC, Vietnam

PLATFORM DEVELOPER INTERN

May 2021 – Sept 2021

- Project: Student Information System (SIS)
- Collaborated with the academic team to conduct UI/UX research, refactorize, and build a part of the SIS system to automatically record the academic performance of more than 200 students.
- Worked and reported directly to the Chief Academic Officer to provide administrative support, and give recommendations for the SIS reform to improve 30% of TA(s) productivity.

Honours & Awards.

Fully-Funded Optimas Capital Scholarship, The University of Hong Kong2023AI Consulting Mentorship Programme, QuantumBlack, AI by McKinsey2022First Prize of AlxIMPACT Case Competition, QuantumBlack, AI by McKinsey2022Country First Runner Up of 3M Inspire Challenge, 3M Vietnam2021

Extracurricular Activity

MindFulbright Website HCMC, Vietnam

PROJECT LEAD

Oct 2021 - Now

- Scope& prioritize activities for design, development, and content team to provide a set of Mindfulness practices for more than 500 users of Fulbright community.
- Prepare detailed functional specification documents for required development activities.

References.

Professor Le Vu Quan

Former Academic Director,
The University of Hong Kong in Vietnam
lv.quan@iced.org.vn

Professor Khieu Van Hoang

Assitant Professor in Macroeconomics, Fulbright University Vietnam hoang.khieu@fulbright.edu.vn

Professor Phan Tuan-Ngoc

Assitant Professor in Political Economy, Fulbright University Vietnam ngoc.phan@fulbright.edu.vn

Professor Chicheng Ma

Associate Professor in Development Economics, The University of Hong Kong

Miscellaneous_

Programming Languages Python, R, Stata, SQL (Intermediate), LTEX

Software and Tools GIS (learning), GitHub, Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel & Powerpoint)

Languages English, Vietnam, Mandarin (Learning)

Citizenship Vietnamese

JULY 18, 2024 SHAYNE NGUYEN · CV 2